<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on while my code&#39;s compiling</title>
    <link>https://cha.dweimer.com/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on while my code&#39;s compiling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 15:24:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cha.dweimer.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>web programming sure has changed</title>
      <link>https://cha.dweimer.com/2016/07/16/web-programming-sure-has-changed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 15:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cha.dweimer.com/2016/07/16/web-programming-sure-has-changed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I finally started a blog. I always said I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t, but here we are. I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure what changed, other than the fact that I recently purchased a few domain names, including this site, and was looking for ways to utilize them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been really into web development, in particular learning some of the modern techniques that didn&amp;rsquo;t exist when I had last done web programming (circa 2000). Back then I had been using the traditional LAMP stack, using traditional &amp;ldquo;inline&amp;rdquo; PHP inside HTML. It&amp;rsquo;s crazy how much has changed since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started when I decided to develop an &lt;a href=&#34;https://recipebook.wineandcats.com&#34;&gt;online recipe book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; for my wife. She had been trying a few things recently, including Evernote and Google Drive, but nothing seemed to meet her needs. This turned out to be a great opportunity to work towards one of my goals for 2016 which was to learn a new programming language. After some research, I discovered (or rather rediscovered) &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org&#34;&gt;GO&lt;/a&gt; and the great development community it has, especially around web application development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a long story short, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the past few months immersed in the web and all it has to offer. It&amp;rsquo;s been a great experience, both enjoyable and extremely educational, and it&amp;rsquo;s made me a more well-rounded developer. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see where this journey takes me and continue to learn how little I still know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; If you&amp;rsquo;re actually reading this (and if you are, let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, you&amp;rsquo;re probably doing it out of obligation as a friend or family member), check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://github/chadweimer/gomp&#34;&gt;GOMP: GO Meal Planner&lt;/a&gt; for the source code.&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>