<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Page-rsses on while my code&#39;s compiling</title>
    <link>https://cha.dweimer.com/page/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Page-rsses on while my code&#39;s compiling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 16:05:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cha.dweimer.com/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Resumé</title>
      <link>https://cha.dweimer.com/page/about/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 16:05:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cha.dweimer.com/page/about/resume/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10+ years of experience as a Software Engineer developing instrumentation and hardware products in .NET&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5+ years of experience as a Technical Lead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proficient with C#, WPF, MVVM, .NET, Windows Forms, Scrum, Agile, OOP, UI Design, JIRA, TFS, Git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experienced with ASP.NET, C/C++, RDMS (PostgreSQL, SQL Server), HTML, XML, XPath, NAnt, IoC, Go, Polymer, Javascript, NUnit, Design Patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiar with PHP, CSS, Linux, MSBuild, XSLT, ADO.NET, N-Tiered Design, UML, RUP, Subversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;professional-experience&#34;&gt;Professional Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;sr-staff-software-engineer-tech-lead-illumina-inc-san-diego-ca-2011-present&#34;&gt;Sr. Staff Software Engineer, Tech Lead, Illumina, Inc., San Diego, CA, 2011 - Present&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide technical leadership across several of the companies product lines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Host and participate in software design reviews across a wide range of projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;group-lead-aerotech-inc-pittsburgh-pa-2009-2011&#34;&gt;Group Lead, Aerotech, Inc., Pittsburgh, PA, 2009 - 2011&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed the day-to-day activities of up to 5 developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Served as Project Manager on multiple development projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interviewed job applicants, attend recruiting job fairs, and make decisions regarding hiring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promoted the use of IoC (Inversion of Control) design patterns for all component development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;software-engineer-iii-aerotech-inc-pittsburgh-pa-january-2006-2011&#34;&gt;Software Engineer III, Aerotech, Inc., Pittsburgh, PA, January 2006 - 2011&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed Windows applications using C# and WinForms for use in advanced motion control systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used best practices to design high quality controls and components with an emphasis on reuse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interacted directly with customers for both support and custom software design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and implemented the infrastructure for licensing and distributing the company’s software products, including licensing model, license data storage and retrieval, physical media distribution, and upgrade acquisition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lead the development of a CRM system for use company-wide. The application utilized N-Tiered design, with a MS SQL Server back-end and ASP.NET front-end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Successfully designed and implemented an ASP.NET-based issue tracking system for use throughout the company within the first 3 months of employment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-experience&#34;&gt;Other Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;open-source&#34;&gt;Open Source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chadweimer&#34;&gt;https://github.com/chadweimer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;contributions&#34;&gt;Contributions&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Collaborne/paper-search&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Collaborne/paper-search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;software-development-intern-micron-technology-inc-manassas-va-may-december-2004&#34;&gt;Software Development Intern, Micron Technology, Inc., Manassas, VA, May - December 2004&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked a continuous 7 month rotation as an intern assisting the semiconductor manufacturing support team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and implemented a Knowledge Base application using ASP.NET and SQL Server for use by the department and manufacturing floor personnel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilized the Rational Unified Process (RUP) to develop robust, highly stable solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used UML modeling for all application design and analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisted in diagnosing software problems related to the Automated Material Handling System (AMHS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;web-administrator-and-developer-self-employed-rollinbuddy-com-2002-2006&#34;&gt;Web Administrator and Developer, Self Employed (RollinBuddy.com) 2002 - 2006&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creator and developer for RollinBuddy.com, a web site dedicated to providing AOL Instant Messenger buddy icons for automobile enthusiasts, while a full-time undergraduate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Written in XHTML, CSS, and PHP utilizing a MySQL database back-end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Received roughly 50,000 page views per day over a period of 2 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;education-training&#34;&gt;Education &amp;amp; Training&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-pennsylvania-state-university&#34;&gt;The Pennsylvania State University&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B.S. Computer Science, Mathematics Minor, GPA: 3.73, Graduated: December 2005&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;developmentor&#34;&gt;DevelopMentor&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Guerilla.NET&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Essential Windows Forms&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Essential ASP.NET&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Essential Windows Presentation Foundation&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://cha.dweimer.com/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cha.dweimer.com/page/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Chad Weimer and I&amp;rsquo;m a Software Engineering at a large biotech company in San Diego, CA. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the software business for 11 years. In my professional career I&amp;rsquo;ve been primarily focused on instrumentation and hardware control using .NET, but I&amp;rsquo;m also well versed in UI development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no interest in leaving my current job, but out of prudence I keep a (moderately) up-to-date &lt;a href=&#34;https://cha.dweimer.com/page/about/resume&#34;&gt;Resumé&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>